[{"date":"04/12","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Tell me what the Devil’s Dictionary defines as the Hider factor in the progress of the human race.","answer":"Villains"}]},{"date":"04/19","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Between A and B ... which line seems longer ...?","answer":"They’re the same"}]},{"date":"04/23","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Between music, theater, and chariot racing, which sport did Nero win when he participated in the Olympics?","answer":"All of them"}]},{"date":"04/25","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What does the phrase \"My country right or wrong\" mean to convey?","answer":"You unquestionably support it"},{"type":"class-question","question":"But the original meaning was different? So I guess it'd be something like...","answer":"You have a duty to correct it"}]},{"date":"04/27","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know the name of the theorem named after this number?","answer":"Four color theorem"}]},{"date":"04/30","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"First off, the \"wunder\" part probably means ...?","answer":"Wonder"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Next, the \"kind\" part. That’s probably ...","answer":"Child"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Yeah, that’s gotta be it. \"Kind\" means a child ... or at least a young guy, in your case","answer":"A prodigy"}]},{"date":"05/07","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"So what’s the literal translation of the phrase \"femme fatale?\"","answer":"Fatal woman"}]},{"date":"05/10","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"You know the time period Yoshitsune was active in, don’t you?","answer":"The Heian period"}]},{"date":"05/11","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What historical figure inspired \"favoring the magistrate?\"","answer":"Minamoto no Yoshitsune"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Yoshitune had a brother, right. Oh, I think his name was ...","answer":"Minamoto no Yoritomo"},{"type":"class-question","question":"But they ended up coming into conflict. And in the end when they had to oppose each other ...","answer":"Yoritomo won"},{"type":"class-question","question":"That’s probably because people tend to sympathize less with people in power, and sympathize more with ...","answer":"The weak"}]},{"date":"05/12","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Which brain function is responsible for the phenomenon of seeing an illusion in this figure?","answer":"Cognition"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Which of the following maps can you paint without any adjacent areas being the same color?","answer":"Both"}]},{"date":"05/13","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Name that book that defined \"male factor\" as the chief factor in the progress of the human race.","answer":"The Devil’s Dictionary"},{"type":"class-question","question":"What character archetype refers to a mysterious and seductive woman, typically with ulterior motives?","answer":"Femme Fatale"}]},{"date":"05/16","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What do we call the phenomenon where believing in a treatment’s power is enough to improve your condition?","answer":"The Placebo effect"}]},{"date":"05/19","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Which famous artist of the Edo period is said to have moved residence over 100 times?","answer":"Katsushika Hokusai"}]},{"date":"05/21","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"The golden ratio is 1:1.618 but do you know the silver ratio?","answer":"1:1.414"}]},{"date":"05/23","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"If we think about what these words have in common, then maybe \"syn\" means ...","answer":"Together"},{"type":"class-question","question":"And \"aisthesis,\" huh? That’s a little like the word aesthetics. I wonder if it means ...","answer":"Senses"},{"type":"class-question","question":"So that means the full word basically means...","answer":"Senses coming together"}]},{"date":"05/26","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know which author Leblanc borrowed from?","answer":"Arthur Conan Doyle"}]},{"date":"05/31","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know which peg-legged, parrot toting historical figure’s appearance became visual shorthand for pirates?","answer":"John Silver"}]},{"date":"06/04","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What do you think the name for the phenomenon is?","answer":"The halo effect"}]},{"date":"06/07","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"The red king crab is biologically related to the hermit crab. So how is it different from a crab. Do you know?","answer":"The number of legs"}]},{"date":"06/08","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Where does totalitarianism take things a step further than authoritarianism?","answer":"Controlling Public Thought"}]},{"date":"06/13","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What color do you think it turns?","answer":"Green"}]},{"date":"06/15","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Between paper bills and coins, which one is issued by the government?","answer":"Coins"}]},{"date":"06/20","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"One of these has minor metals in it, right?","answer":"Smartphone"}]},{"date":"06/23","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Now do you know what this woman’s position was?","answer":"A pope"}]},{"date":"06/27","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Which of these animals is involved in an English idiom about the weather?","answer":"Dogs"}]},{"date":"06/29","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What do you think it says on the back of this piece?","answer":"Gold"}]},{"date":"07/01","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What’s the meaning of the original Chinese phrase that these dumplings’ name came from?","answer":"Barbarian’s Head"}]},{"date":"07/04","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Two people are responsible for July and August having 31 days. Do you know who those people are?","answer":"Julius and Augustus"}]},{"date":"07/07","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"So Tanabata’s about gods crossing a starry sky to reunite once every year. It might have something to do with... ?","answer":"The Milky Way"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Traditional food","answer":"Soumen’s noodles"}]},{"date":"07/09","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know what shape it is?","answer":"A triangle"}]},{"date":"07/11","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What is long-term memory, anyway?","answer":"Memories that last a long time"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Markus mentioned something about the amount of memories you could store, right? Something like ...","answer":"Infinite"},{"type":"class-question","question":"If you have theoretically infinite space for them... Theoretically, you’d be able to retain them for ...","answer":"Forever"}]},{"date":"07/12","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know what he did?","answer":"Thievery"}]},{"date":"07/13","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"If angle C is 28 degrees, and angles A and D are 88 degrees, what is the angle of B and E?","answer":"64 degrees"},{"type":"class-question","question":"I think this came up in class. They were invented by the campus’s guy from Romance of the Three Kingdoms, right?","answer":"Zhuge Liang"},{"type":"class-question","question":"And they were offering something to quell the river ...","answer":"Barbarians’ heads"},{"type":"class-question","question":"This master strategist came up with the baozi to","answer":"To offer them instead of heads"}]},{"date":"07/14","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What is the name and genus of this organism?","answer":"Red King Crab (Paralithodes)"},{"type":"class-question","question":"What happened when the government issued paper and hard currencies in Japan for the first time?","answer":"It caused confusion in the economy"}]},{"date":"07/15","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What is the English equivalent of the Norwegian idiom \"raining witches?\"","answer":"Raining cats and dogs"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Which of the following is another name for spikenard noodles traditionally eaten in Tanabata?","answer":"Demon guts"}]},{"date":"09/03","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Each hand in this famous statue means something, but ... do you know what the right represents?","answer":"Prosperity"}]},{"date":"09/06","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know the name of that phenomenon where the second hand looks like it’s stopped moving?","answer":"Chronostasis"}]},{"date":"09/14","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What does a pawn shop offer that a secondhand shop doesn’t?","answer":"Money loans for collateral"}]},{"date":"09/17","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What’s one of the supposed origins for the phrase \"cat got your tongue?\"","answer":"Cats eating human tongues"}]},{"date":"09/21","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Robot comes from a word in Czech ... but where in Europe is the Czech Republic located?","answer":"Central Europe"}]},{"date":"09/24","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"How many white and black shapes are there respectively on a soccer ball?","answer":"20 white, 12 black"}]},{"date":"09/28","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"So \"PVS,\" referring to when you mistakenly think your phone is going off... What's the P?","answer":"Phantom"},{"type":"class-question","question":"The next part is the V part. That means it'd be \"phantom...\" what?","answer":"Vibration"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Last is the S. So if we have \"phantom vibration\" so far...?","answer":"Syndrome"}]},{"date":"09/29","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"But the fishermen of Nagaragawa are actually civil servants as well. So, tell me which sector they belong to.","answer":"Imperial Household Agency"}]},{"date":"10/03","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"If we use \"three watermelons in the sun\" to visualize a certain matter’s size against the universe’s, what are the melons?","answer":"Stars"}]},{"date":"10/06","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Now, do you know who invented this instrument?","answer":"Joseph-Ignace Guillotine"}]},{"date":"10/11","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Which name was most commonly ascribed to shape B?","answer":"Bouba"}]},{"date":"10/17","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Counting both black and white surfaces, how many surfaces are there in total on a soccer ball?","answer":"32 surfaces"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Didn’t the teacher say that the number of colors used to be different? Do you remember?","answer":"It used to be one color"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Oh yeah, I remember. I think she said that unlike now, soccer games were broadcast with ...","answer":"Black and white picture"}]},{"date":"10/18","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Who conducted executions using this device?","answer":"Charles-Henri Sanson"},{"type":"class-question","question":"What is the reason that most people can not become a commercial fisherman of Nagarasawa?","answer":"It’s a hereditary profession"}]},{"date":"10/19","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What is the meaning of \"robota,\" the etymological root of \"robot\"?","answer":"Slave labor"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Which of the following describes the density of the stars in outer space?","answer":"3 bees in all of Europe"}]},{"date":"10/22","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Now, tell me the total count for each column in this magic square.","answer":"15"}]},{"date":"10/24","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"From a psychological standpoint, what’s a key reason our memories can differ from reality?","answer":"Memory Bias"}]},{"date":"11/02","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Can you tell me the meaning of the word \"wack\" in Thieves’ Cant?","answer":"A share of stolen goods"}]},{"date":"11/04","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Clubs is a club, diamond is a gem, so what does a spade represent?","answer":"A sword"}]},{"date":"11/08","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Tell me how old you have to be to listen in on a trial?","answer":"Any age"}]},{"date":"11/10","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know why it’s missing in the character for crow?","answer":"Crow eyes are hard to see"}]},{"date":"11/12","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"I wonder. Do you know why voices sound so different over the phone?","answer":"Because the voice is synthetic."}]},{"date":"11/14","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Tell me why that is?","answer":"Because of high altitude"}]},{"date":"11/15","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"He was to be paraded through the city and punished in a very particular way. How was he punished?","answer":"His head was put on display"}]},{"date":"11/17","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know the name for this graph? Your hint is \"snails\" ...","answer":"Cochleoid"}]},{"date":"12/20","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Choose the graph which is named after the Chinese yoyo known as a diabolo.","answer":"D"},{"type":"class-question","question":"He was a really famous thief in the Edo period, right? How much money did he steal, in the end?","answer":"Over one billion yen"},{"type":"class-question","question":"As a result he was sentenced to ...","answer":"Having his head displayed"},{"type":"class-question","question":"Criminals, especially famous criminals, were mostly parades around for ...","answer":"A performance"}]},{"date":"12/21","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Which suit of cards represents the Holy Grail?","answer":"Hearts"},{"type":"class-question","question":"According to Japanese judicial law, what is possible for even an infant to do in court?","answer":"Attend"}]},{"date":"12/22","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What country refers to a person who controls politics behind the scenes as a \"prime minister in black?\"","answer":"Japan"},{"type":"class-question","question":"The Japanese word \"dokyuu\" translates to \"massive.\" What English word inspired the initial \"do\" in dokyuu?","answer":"Dreadnought"}]},{"date":"01/11","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What’s this phrase supposed to illustrate about the gods of Shinto?","answer":"How numerous they are"},{"type":"class-question","question":"What’s the phrase again? The one about how many gods there are in Shinto?","answer":"The Eight Million Gods"}]},{"date":"01/14","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Where do you think the fictional land of \"Ihatov\" is modeled after?","answer":"Iwate"}]},{"date":"01/18","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What did the word awful originally mean?","answer":"Impressive"}]},{"date":"01/20","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"Do you know what she’s stepping on?","answer":"A snake"}]},{"date":"01/24","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"What does that mean when describing a person?","answer":"Kind-hearted"},{"type":"class-question","question":"So what kind of connotation would \"salty\" have in that context?","answer":"Negative"},{"type":"class-question","question":"So with all of that in mind, \"salty\" probably means ...","answer":"Resentful"}]},{"date":"01/27","events":[{"type":"class-question","question":"How far did this study suggest personal happiness can spread?","answer":"To friends of friends of friends"}]}]